copart.co.uk 2016-11-19

# Copart UK Privacy Policy - Copart

    **  Privacy Policy **

Last updated on: 19 September 2016

**What This Privacy Policy Covers**

This policy governs the website operated at [www.copart.co.uk](http://www.copart.co.uk/), any the information prac­tices of and any other electronic services or applications (the “Electronic Services”) offered by Copart UK Limited (“Copart UK”), Copart UAE Auctions LLC (“Copart UAE”) and Copart, Inc. (“Copart”) their parent corporation based in the United States of America. By providing personal information through our website or any Electronic Services and to us you understand and acknowledge that you are providing your personal informa­tion to both Copart UK and Copart (and, if you are based in the United Arab Emirates or buy vehicles located in the UAE, also to Copart UAE). Personal information is information about you that is personally identifiable, such as your name, address, email address, or phone number, and that is not otherwise publicly available.

This policy does not apply to the practices of companies that Copart UK, Copart UAE or Copart do not own or control or to people that Copart UK or Copart UAE does not employ or manage.

**Information Collection and Use**

We collect personal information when you register with us and when you use our services.

When you register with us we may ask for information such as your name, address, email address, phone number, credit card information, business licence information, driving li­cence information, postcode, and other financial information. Once you register with us and log in to use our services, you are not anonymous to us.

We collect information about your transactions with us, including information regarding items you bid on.

We automatically receive and record information on our server logs regarding your ses­sions on the Copart UK, Copart UAE and Copart websites and those of their subsidiaries, and (if you have set your computer to receive cookies) related cookie information. For fur­ther information, see the section below headed “Cookies”.

We use information for the following general purposes: to contact you, to facilitate bidding, buying, and selling of items by you through Copart UK, Copart UAE and Copart, to transfer title and ownership of items bought and sold by you, and to comply with laws and regula­tions related to purchases and sales of items by you through us.

**Information Sharing and Disclosure**

We do not rent, sell, or share personal information about you with other people or non­affiliated companies except to (i) provide products or services you’ve requested, (ii) when we have your permission, or (iii) under the following circumstances:

  * we provide the information to trusted partners who work on behalf of or with us under confidentiality agreements and in accordance with law. These companies may use your personal information to help us communicate with you about offers from us. However, these companies do not have any independent right to share this informa­tion;
  * we provide the information in response to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims, or upon receipt of a valid request from law enforcement agencies (such as the police and Trading Stan­dards);
  * we do not otherwise share personal information about website users with third parties unless doing so is appropriate to carry out a user’s request or it reasonably believes that doing so is legally required or is in our interest to protect its property or other legal rights or the rights or property of others;
  * we may transfer information about you if Copart UK or Copart is acquired by or merged with another company to the extent permitted by applicable law. In this event, we will notify you before information about you is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy;
  * we transfer information about you to sellers of items purchased by you, to buyers of items sold by you and to their service providers that they may retain to facilitate the as­signment of items to our sales venues, and to governmental agencies when required to facilitate the ownership transfer process.
  * If you apply to become a member of Copart, we may transfer your personal data to third parties for the purpose of carrying out checks to verify your identity and credit status. This means that as well as other checks, your personal data may be used to undertake a full electoral roll search. Third party credit reference agencies may place a search footprint on any electronic file held by such agencies about you and your personal details may be accessed by third parties for the specific purpose of anti-money laundering, credit assessment, identity verification, debt collection, asset reunification, tracing and fraud prevention.

**International Visitors and Customers**

The Copart UK and Copart UAE web sites are hosted in the United States of America by Copart on our behalf. The personal data provided through the Electronic Services may be stored outside the EU by our third party service provider. The United States has not been determined to provide adequate data protection. However, where any customer data or personal data may be transferred to a third party service provider outside the EU, Copart only does so on the basis of a written contract which incorporates obligations for the protection of such data in accordance with standards set by the EU, also known as a model clause contract. Accordingly, when visiting our website or providing personal data to us, we have taken steps to ensure the adequate

Please note that you are transferring your personal data to the United States and other non-EU countries. By provid­ing your personal data you consent to:

  * the use of your personal data for the purposes identified above in accordance with this privacy policy; and
  * the transfer of your personal data to the United States and non-EU countries as indicated above.

**Cookies**

We may place a text file called a “cookie” in the browser files of your computer or mobile device. The cookie itself does not contain personal information although it will enable us to relate your use of Copart websites or Electronic Services to information that you have specifically and knowingly provided. But the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. A cookie can’t read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other websites.

We may use cookies to track user traffic patterns on Copart websites or Electronic Services, but we do not use cookies to track your use of third party websites.

In addition, we use encrypted cookies to authenticate the user on each page after the user logs on to our website or Electronic Services. It is not possible to log in to our members’ area with­out accepting these cookies – this means you cannot bid on Copart UK or Copart UAE lots without accepting these cookies.

Accepting the log-in cookies will enable you to access the members’ area of our website or Electronic Services, but some other features and services (for example creating customised searches for vehi­cles) may not function properly or conveniently if your other cookies are disabled.

You can refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser. Alternatively you can set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies; this means you will receive the warning message with each cookie.

**Communications**

We reserve the right to send you certain communications relating to our services and your account with us, including but not limited to notifications, service announcements, and administrative messages without offering you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving them (although we will obtain your consent at the time you create your account). Should you choose not to receive such communications your continued access to or use of our services may not be possible.

**Data Storage**

We may store your account information in our databases indefinitely following the termi­nation of your account with us to the maximum extent permitted by law.

**Confidentiality and Security**

We limit access to personal information about you to employees who we believe reasonably need to come into contact with that information to provide products or services to you or in order to do their jobs.

We have physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with our legal respon­sibilities to protect personal information about you.

If we learn of a security systems breach we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. By using our website or Electronic Services or providing personal in­formation to us you agree that we can communicate with you electronically regarding secu­rity, privacy and administrative issues relating to your use of this website or Electronic Services. We may post a notice on our website if a security breach occurs. We may also send an email to you at the email address you have provided to us in these circumstances. Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing. To receive free written notice of a security breach (or, if you are an individual, to withdraw your con­sent from receiving electronic notices) you should notify us at [privacy@copart.co.uk](mailto:privacy@copart.co.uk).

We take your security seriously and take reasonable steps to protect your information. No data transmission over the Internet or information storage technology can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. The following is a summary of the measures we take to protect your information and descriptions of ways we implement these measures for different types of information you may provide to us:

  * _Secure Socket Layer (SSL)_

We use SSL encryption when transmitting certain kinds of information, such as finan­cial services information or payment information. An icon resembling a padlock is dis­played on the bottom of most browsers window during SSL transactions that involve credit cards and other forms of payment. Any time we ask you for a credit card number for payment or for verification purposes, it will be SSL encrypted. The information you provide will be stored securely on our servers. Once you choose to store or enter your credit card number, it will not be displayed back to you in its entirety when you retrieve or edit it in the future. Instead of the entire number, you will only see asterisks and ei­ther the first four digits or the last four digits of your number.

  * _Vendors and Partners_

We work with vendors and partners to protect the security and privacy of user informa­tion.

  * _Employee and Contractor Access to Information_

We limit access to personal information about you to those employees who we rea­sonably believe need to come into contact with that information to provide products or services to you or in order to do their jobs.

  * _Education and Training for Employees_

We have implemented a company-wide education and training program about security that is required of every Copart UK and Copart UAE employee.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

We may update this policy. When we do, we will also revise the date at the start of this document. For changes to this policy that may be materially less restrictive on our use or disclosure of personal information you have provided to us, we will attempt to obtain your consent before implementing the change. We encourage you to periodically review this policy to stay informed about how we are protecting the information we collect. Your con­tinued use of this website constitutes your agreement to this policy and any updates.

**Questions and Suggestions**

If you have questions or suggestions about our Privacy Policy, please contact us at [privacy@copart.co.uk](mailto:privacy@copart.co.uk)
